So guys, the next core exercise that we're going to do is crunches and we're going to start using a stability ball to make the crunches a bit harder, more progressive.
Grab a ball, lie down on the mat, take your feet and we're going to start with your feet on the ball just like so.
We're going to interlace fingers behind your head, exhale, think about your elbows coming up and then right back down.
You'll feel that with your legs on the ball you'll start to engage your lower abdominals.
So you're going to exhale and then back down, exhale and back down, exhale and back down, exhale and back down.
Each time pull the belly button in towards your spine, feel nice and tall through the top of your head and then lie back down.
Feel the ribcage is working its way to the thighs and then back down.
Then once after you do a set then we can try a little more progressiveness and we're going to slide the ball away from your body and then we're going to roll the legs in and then back out.
So roll the legs in and touch and then back out, roll in and out, exhale roll in and out, exhale roll in and out, exhale roll in and out, exhale roll in and out, exhale roll in and out, exhale roll in and out.
Then once you're done with that if you like to bring your feet down on the ground like we did last week, you do the last set of crunches without the ball.
Touch, down, touch, down, touch, down, touch, down, touch and down.
Go for it!